# Ardian Bahtiarsyah, Software Engineer

Pekalongan, Indonesia, +6285640493930, ardian.bahtiarsyah@gmail.com

PROFILE

As an experienced software engineer with over 10 years of experience and a strong desire to build and create, I have successfully founded and launched some products from the ground up, which have provided me with not only valuable technical expertise but also a unique perspective on business operations.

I am also currently serving as an engineering manager to expand my people management skills within the software development industry.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Dec 2017 — Present

# Software Engineer & Founder, Apisentris

Pekalongan, Remote

Apisentris is a platform that converts any databases to RESTful APIs. Apisentris is a weekend project and a solo journey. This is also proof that I have a big commitment to something I have an interest in.

#### Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Successfully founded and launched Apisentris from scratch as MVP features.
- Achieving a top rank of 11th on Product Hunt on the day of its second iteration.
   <u>https://www.producthunt.com/products/apisentris#apisentris-2</u>. This was a major accomplishment as it was the first time I brought my own product to the market.
- Secured the Apisentris' first paying customer from an international user, effectively demonstrating my
  ability to wear multiple hats and excel from software engineering to customer success.
- Now Apisentris is on autopilot and pays the infra cost by itself.

Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Docker, Nginx

Apr 2021 — Present

# Engineering Manager, Quipper Ltd.

Jakarta, Remote

Quipper is an education technology company that provides e-learning, coaching, tutoring, and assessment services for K-12 students in Japan, Indonesia, and the Philippines.

#### Responsibilities:

- Collaborate with the product managers and stakeholders to ensure the development is meet the standards
  of delivery.
- Facilitate sprint cadences with all team members involved.
- Measure the product's KPIs to meet the baseline.
- Supervise engineers working in Quipper Video business unit and ensure team members' growth.
- Direct report to VP of Engineering

#### Achievements:

- Achieved a significant improvement in cycle time, reducing the average time from development and testing to deployment to below 3 working days, where previously it had not been measured.
- Consistently exceeded expectations by maintaining a delivery rate above 90% on average, which was
  previously not measured.
- Successfully increased test coverage from 30% to 80% on average, with some features owned by the team
  achieving 100% test coverage.
- Consistently met and exceeded industry standards by maintaining an error rate of the product below 0.1%, surpassing the Service Level Objective of 99.9%.

Oct 2020 — Mar 2021

#### Lead Software Engineer, Quipper Ltd.

Jakarta, Remote

## Responsibilities:

- · Leading the Quipper Video team to deliver product features.
- Coordinate tasks among the Quipper Video team members.
- Analyze data and track metrics of the features that are owned by the Quipper Video team.
- Maintain technical documentation for Quipper Video features.

#### Achievements:

 Successfully led the launch of the most demanded feature in Quipper Video business unit, Video & Quiz Search. This increased the student's learning time by 300%.

- Improved content discovery by 80% with an accurate search function using Elastic Search.
- Introduced Golang to the Quipper Video team and implemented it for the Topic Recommendation service and Student Statistics service.

Tech Stack: Golang, Ruby, ReactJS with Typescript, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, BigQuery, Firebase, ElasticSearch, Embulk for data pipeline, Kubernetes

Jan 2020 — Sep 2020

# Senior Software Engineer, Quipper Ltd.

Jakarta, Remote

#### Responsibilities:

- · Maintain and improve on common core features (features that are leveraged by services. e.g: user account management, video chapters, quizzes, etc).
- Maintain and improve API integrity (e.g. define modularization architecture strategy, API structure, etc).
- Ensure interoperability between services.

#### Achievements:

- · Introduced event-driven architecture on the subscription synchronization using Google Pubsub, this is to be expected to decrease the data discrepancies by 100% on the payment information received.
- · Developed and deployed a personalized campaign as an individual contributor, successfully delivering a tailored experience to customers.
- · Developed and deployed a "Let's Learn Again" as an individual contributor, providing a valuable learning experience to users.

Tech Stack: Ruby, ReactJS with Typescript, MongoDB, BigQuery, Jenkins, Kubernetes

Mar 2017 — Dec 2019

## Senior Software Engineer, Forstok

Jakarta, Hybrid

Forstok is a cloud-based, channel management platform that automates multi-channel retail business to boost sales.

### Responsibilities:

- One of the founding members ensures the development meets the business requirements.
- Research and development on Indonesia's marketplace API integration.
- · Develop public API and maintain technical documentation.

## Achievements:

- Reduced the marketplace API integration time by 75%, from 2 months to 2 weeks through the unification of the logic using a code generator.
- Successfully integrated 7 major marketplaces and e-commerce in Indonesia during tenure.

Tech Stack: Ruby, Elastic Beanstalk, Aurora PostgreSQL

May 2014 — Feb 2017

#### Senior Software Engineer, Qivtech

Bandung, Remote

Qivtech is a software development agency in Bandung.

## Responsibilities:

- Develop web applications based on client's requirements.
- Ensure the scope of the feature is within the time frame and budget.
- Work closely and collaborate with team members to ensure the development is meet the best practices.
- Report directly to Chief Technology Officer.

### Achievements:

• 100% successful client projects and zero contract termination.

Tech Stack: NodeJS, Ruby, AngularJS, PostgreSQL, CSS Bootstrap, Linux, Nginx

Jan 2015 — Feb 2017

## Software Engineer, Phybbit

Tokyo, Remote

Phybbit is a software development agency in Tokyo, Japan.

### Responsibilities:

- Develop web applications based on client's requirements.
- Collaborate with multi-national team members to ensure the development uses the best practices.
- Report directly to Chief Technology Officer.

Tech Stack: Ruby, NodeJS, PostgreSQL, AngularJS, AWS EC2, Hubot

Jan 2014 — Feb 2017

# Software Engineer, Madain

Madain is a software development agency that I founded with my software engineer colleagues.

### Responsibilities:

- Ensure the client requirements meet the resource allocation and budget.
- Develop web and mobile applications based on the client's requirements.

#### **Achievements:**

- Zero contract termination.
- 90% of projects were delivered before the deadline.

Nov 2012 — Apr 2014

# Software Engineer, Walden Global Service, PT

Bandung

#### Responsibilities:

• Responsible for designing, coding, and modifying websites, from layout to function and according to a client's specifications.

#### Achievements:

• Handled 20+ web projects during my 1.5 years of tenure with various tech stack and difficulties.

### PORTFOLIO

# Apisentris

https://apisentris.com

Launched on Product Hunt:

https://www.producthunt.com/products/apisentris#apisentris-2

Tech Stack: Ruby, PostgreSQL, Docker, Nginx

Speeech

https://speeech.app

This is work in progress weekends project. <u>Speech</u> is a mobile application that helps the user to learn on how to pronounce English words with AI.

Tech Stack: NodeJS, Flutter, Microsoft Azure Text-to-Speech API, PostgreSQL

SKILLS

JavaScript NodeJS BigQuery

Ruby

Firebase

Ruby

Git

Golang

Docker

Rust

Kubernetes

ReactJS

Envoy

SQL

Managing People

NoSQL

Agile Software Development

### COURSES

Mar 2022 — Mar 2022

# High Performing Manager, Top Coach Indonesia

LANGUAGES

English

Good working knowledge

Indonesian

Native speaker

#### **EDUCATION**

Apr 2008 — Mar 2012

# Bachelor Degree, Universitas Dian Nuswantoro

Semarang

Bachelor of Computer Science

Honors: cum laude (GPA 3.64 / 4.00)